Guide to the Stanford University, Faculty Senate, Records SC0193
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Faculty Senate, records
1891-2016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Faculty Senate
Stanford University. Academic Council
SC0193
131.5 Linear Feet
These records were generated by the Faculty Senate, Academic Council, the Academic Senate, the Academic Secretary, and various committees and task forces. They include minutes, memoranda, correspondence, reports, election records, agendas and supporting documents, rosters, memorial resolutions on deceased members, and audiotapes of meetings. The collection also includes minutes from faculty meetings prior to the creation of the Academic Council, 1891-1904. Some of the issues addressed by the committees include admissions, academic freedom, athletics, undergraduate education, foreign studies programs, graduate studies, public health, education and employment of women in the University, student government, and student political activities.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
These records have been transferred in several different accessions from 1978 to the present.
Information about Access
The materials are restricted 20 years from date of creation.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Academic Council was organized by the Stanford University faculty in 1904 and currently consists of members of the Professoriate and certain officers of the academic administration as specified by the Articles of Organization. The Council holds one regularly scheduled meeting annually. The Advisory Board of the Academic Council is composed of seven members of the rank of Professor and addresses issues of appointments, promotions, dismissals, creation of new departments, and other policy matters as presented to it by the University President.
In 1968 the Academic Council created the Senate of the Academic Council, composed of representatives elected from the Council. The Senate meets monthly from October through June and is responsible for carrying out the functions of the Council. The Academic Secretary is responsible for communicating the decisions and actions of the Senate to every member of the Council.
Description of the Collection
These records were generated by the Academic Council, the Academic Senate, the Academic Secretary, and various committees and task forces. They include minutes, memoranda, correspondence, reports, election records, agendas and supporting documents, rosters, memorial resolutions on deceased members, and audiotapes of meetings. The collection also includes minutes from faculty meetings prior to the creation of the Academic Council, 1891-1904. Some of the issues addressed by the committees include admissions, academic freedom, athletics, undergraduate education, foreign studies programs, graduate studies, public health, education and employment of women in the University, student government, and student political activities.
Existence and Location of Copies
Faculty Senate records have been digitized and are available online here: https://exhibits.stanford.edu/stanford-senate.
Women -- Education (Higher); Universities and colleges -- Faculty.; Stanford University. Faculty Senate; Stanford University. Academic Council; Stanford University. Academic Secretary; Stanford University. Academic Secretary; Stanford University. Faculty Senate; Stanford University; Stanford University
- Academic Council records, 1966-1975; Series 1
  - Establishment of the Senate, 06/30/1966 - 12/18/1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Senate proposal
  - Establishment of the Senate, 01/18/1968 - 03/05/1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Redrafts of Senate proposal; statement of procedure of voting by the Hare System.
  - Establishment of the Senate, 03/05/1968 - 05/14/1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Report to the Academic Council on the Senate Charter; Allocation of representatives to the Senate; memos on voting procedure.
  - Establishment of the Senate, 06/13/1967 - 05/14/1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Principles and procedures for voting; tallies for representatives; results of balloting by electoral unit.
  - Executive Committee, 11/02/1967 - 12/12/1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Activity requirement; Advisory Board eligibility; Assoc. of College Senates; ASSU Professor Commission; Athletic Policy; attendance; council meetings; building construction; Chancellor member; election groups; General Studies - waiver of requirements; Honor Code (dated 4/20/1967)
  - Executive Committee, 04/01/1960 - 03/15/1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Hoover Institution; Interdepartmental majors (Afro-American and American Studies); Interdepartmental majors H & S; minority problems; optional finals; overseas campuses; pass/fail; Ph.D. oral.
  - Executive Committee, 02/03/1967 - 06/26/1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Rank in class; ROTC; Selective Service; Legislative and Judicial Charter; special meetings; tenure statement; tuition exchange.
  - Executive Committee, 02/07/1967 - 12/18/1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Minutes, Calls, & Agendas.
  - Executive Committee, 01/05/1968 - 07/11/1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Minutes, calls, & agendas.
  - 1st Senate, 07/01/1968 - 08/07/1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Senate reports.
  - 1st Senate, 06/20/1968 - 04/24/1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Senate minutes.
  - 1st Senate, 04/28/1969 - 08/07/1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Senate minutes; joint meetings of Senate & Student Education Council.
  - 1st Senate (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Placement service; Public Events (C-PEV); Radiological Hazards (C-RHC); relations with student government.
  - 1st Senate (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Research (C-RES).
  - 1st Senate, 02/11/1969 - 03/05/1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    ROTC (AC-ROTC).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 3, Folder 3)
    NIH supply allowances; Ombudsman; overseas campus programs; parking & traffic; pass/fail grading; police intervention.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Preregistration & orientation; purloined papers; relations with student government.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Research policy.
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 11/05/1968 - 03/05/1969 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Study of Education at Stanford (SES).
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 03/10/1969 - 08/31/1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 09/01/1969 - 12/31/1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) resolution; Stanford Research Institute (SRI).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Staff tuition benefits; Steering Committee elections; Steering Committee procedures; students on committees; teaching assistants.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Trustee relations; US Senate investigations; University Advisory Committee; U.C. Berkeley.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 4, Folder 7)
    University budget; University division; University governance; University staff
  - 1st Senate, 07/03/1968 - 01/30/1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Steering Committee (StC) minutes.
  - 1st Senate, 02/03/1969 - 07/28/1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1st Senate, 07/29/1968 - 03/25/1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Committee on Committees (CoC) minutes.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Committee on Athletics and Physical Education (C-APE); Committee on Business and Financial operations (C-BFO); University Computer Committee (C-CF); Committee on the Education and Employment of Women (C-EEWOMEN); Committee on Faculty and Staff Affairs (C-FSA); Committee on Health (C-Hth); Committee on Land and Building Development (C-LBD).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Committee on Long Range Goals and Planning (C-LRGP); Committee on Public Events (C-PEV); Committee on Student Services (C-SES); Union Committee (C-TMU).
  - 1st Senate, 04/11/1969 - 10/08/1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Advisory Board; Committee on the Bookstore; Committee on Minorities.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Academic calendar; Admissions; Articles of organization of the faculty; ASSU Constitution; business & financial operations; campus disruption policy (C-DIS); campus disruption - Encina sit-in.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Campus disruption - SEL sit-in; campus disruption - SRI disorder; campus disruption - misc. & general.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Committee on Committees (CoC) worksheets and six reports.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Committee of Fifteen (C-15); credit for ASSU; dead week; degrees: African & Afro-American Studies; degrees: conferral; degrees: co-terminal; degrees: Latin American Studies; degrees: Law; degrees: Master of Educational Administration.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Committee on Committee review of committee structure - Volume 1: initial inquiry, general.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Committees of the Academic Council: C-APH; C-FSP; C-GS; C-LIB.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Committees of the Academic Council: C-RES; C-UAFA; C-US; C-UP.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 7, Folder 1)
    ROTC
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Search committee; Senate attendance of members; Senate Charter; Senate elections.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Senate guests & requests; Senate: rosters & directory.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Senate rules.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Degrees: MFA; degrees: Ph.D. orals; degrees: Religious Studies; document index (empty); financial aids.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Foreign language (COFLAS); General Studies; Graduate Student Association; Hoover Institution; housing - low cost; Human Relations Commission (HRC).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Information officer & press representative; Judicial: SJC & policies; Legislative: SCLC.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Meeting schedules & arrangements; memberships & privileges; minority programs.
  - 2nd Senate (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 2nd Senate, 05/19/1969 - 01/22/1970 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 2nd Senate, 02/04/1970 - 06/11/1970 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 2nd Senate, 25659 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    ROTC correspondence; Academic Council - ROTC.
  - 2nd Senate (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Search committees; Senate attendance; Senate elections; Senate guests.
  - 2nd Senate (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Rosters; rules; SRI; Services to students (C-SSt).
  - 2nd Senate, 06/05/1969 - 01/30/1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Steering Committee minutes.
  - 2nd Senate, 02/10/1970 - 07/31/1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 2nd Senate, 07/23/1969 - 01/29/1970 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 2nd Senate, 02/02/1970 - 07/29/1970 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Academic adjustments; Academic calendar; Alumni Relations; Articles of Organization - Faculty; Advisory Board elections.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 9, Folder 6)
    ASSU Professor; Athletics & P.E. (C-APE); Awards, Prizes, and Honors (C-APH); Business & Financial Operations (C-BFO).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Campus disruption.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Campus protest - Ombudsman's interim study group; Committee of Fifteen (C-15).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Committee on Committees (CoC) evaluation; CoC reports.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Canvas of interest in committees (returned faculty interest forms arranged by alpha): A - C.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Canvas of interest in committees (returned faculty interest forms arranged by alpha): D - H.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Canvas of interest in committees (returned faculty interest forms arranged by alpha): I - N.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Canvas of interest in committees (returned faculty interest forms arranged by alpha): O - Z.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 10, Folder 6)
    CoC worksheets.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Community/Faculty self-discipline; Computation facilities (C-CF); Dean's Council.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Degrees: including co-terminal degrees.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Education/Employment of Women (C-EEWU); Environment; External Affirmative Action (C-EAA).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Faculty handbook (C-FHb); Faculty Staff Affairs (C-FSA).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Foreign Policy; Foreign Study Programs (C-FSP).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Ketcham case.
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 12/05/1969 - 03/09/1970 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Land & Building Development (C-LBD) charge & minutes.
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 03/16/1970 - 08/31/1970 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    C-LIB minutes.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Legislation (SCLC); Libraries (C-LIB); meeting schedules
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Membership & Privileges (C-MP).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Minority Affairs (C-MAf); Ombudsman; pass/fail grading.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Committee on Foreign Study Programs - Austria (C-FSP-A); C-FSP-Britain; C-FSP-France.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 12, Folder 2)
    C-FSP-Germany; C-FSP-Italy; C-FSP-Mexico.
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 11/18/1969 - 09/29/1970 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    Committee on Graduate Studies (C-GS) minutes; also includes: Grievance procedure; Health (C-Hth).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 12, Folder 4)
    Housing Advisory Committee (HAC); Human Relations (HRC); investment policy.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Judicial (SJC).
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 01/07/1970 - 04/16/1970 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Undergraduate Studies (C-US).
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 04/21/1970 - 08/17/1970 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 01/07/1970 - 05/20/1970 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    C-US subcommittee on Advising & the Freshman year - minutes.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 13, Folder 1)
    C-US curricular development; C-US extra-departmental courses & interschool majors; C-US policy board; C-US writing.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 13, Folder 2)
    University budget (AC-UBAP); University of California resolutions; University governance; University Press (C-UP); Vietnam Moratorium; Washington delegation.
  - 2nd Senate (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Steering Committee elections; procedures & reports - Committee on Student Evaluation of Teaching (C-SET); Student Involvement in Politics (C-SIPP).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Students on committees; Study of Education (SES).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Tresidder Union (C-TMU); Undergraduate Admissions & Financial Aids.
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 10/25/1969 - 07/15/1970 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Committee on Undergraduate Studies (C-US) minutes.
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 11/03/1970 - 07/28/1971 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Committee on Computer Facilities (C-CF) minutes.
  - 2nd Senate, 09/21/1970 - 02/08/1971 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Constituency meetings.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Degrees: includes lists; Education & Employment of Women (C-EEWU).
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 09/01/1970 - 12/31/1970 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Faculty political action; faculty self-discipline
  - 3rd Senate, 05/26/1970 - 06/10/1971 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 3rd Senate, 05/20/1970 - 02/26/1971 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 3rd Senate, 03/04/1971 - 06/22/1971 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Residential Education (C-RES); ROTC (AC-ROTC); search committees; Senate attendance.
  - 3rd Senate (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Senate Charter.
  - 3rd Senate (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Senate election; Senate guests; Senate rosters.
  - 3rd Senate (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Senate rules; Committee on Services to Students (C-SSt); Stanford police; SRI; Steering Committee elections; Steering Committee procedures.
  - 3rd Senate, 11/09/1970 - 04/28/1971 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Committee on Committees (CoC) evaluations.
  - 3rd Senate, 05/04/1971 - 09/10/1971 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - 3rd Senate, 01/20/1970 - 06/07/1971 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Committee on Committees (CoC) reports.
  - 3rd Senate (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Committee on Committees (CoC) worksheets.
  - 3rd Senate, 06/11/1970 - 09/25/1970 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - 3rd Senate, 10/05/1970 - 02/24/1971 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - 3rd Senate, 03/01/1971 - 06/23/1971 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - 3rd Senate, 05/28/1970 - 12/28/1970 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - 3rd Senate, 01/14/1971 - 06/04/1971 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - 3rd Senate, 01/01/1971 - 08/31/1971 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Faculty self-discipline; Franklin case.
  - 3rd Senate (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Faculty & Staff Affairs (C-FSA); C-FSA Professoriate venture.
  - 3rd Senate, 02/03/1971 - 06/02/1971 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Committee of Fifteen (C-15) minutes.
  - 3rd Senate (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Foreign policy; Foreign Study Programs (C-FSP).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Advisory Board; Alumni Association; ASSU Constitution.
  - 3rd Senate, 10/22/1970 - 04/21/1971 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    C-APE; C-APH minutes
  - 3rd Senate (Box 17, Folder 5)
    Business & Finance; campus disruption.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Information officer & press; investment policy; Judicial (SJC); Justice Department.
  - 3rd Senate, 09/28/1971 - 01/25/1971 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    Committee on Land & Building Development (C-LBD) minutes.
  - 3rd Senate, 02/22/1971 - 08/02/1971 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - 3rd Senate (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Libraries: C-LIB & OLC; Long Range Planning (C-LRP).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Meeting schedules; membership in Academic Council; Minority Affairs (C-MAf).
  - 3rd Senate, 10/20/1970 - 01/14/1971 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - 3rd Senate, 02/02/1971 - 07/01/1971 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - 3rd Senate, 05/03/1971 - 07/14/1971 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Committee on Undergraduate Studies (C-US)/Student Center for Innovation in Research and Education (SCIRE).
  - 3rd Senate (Box 18, Folder 6)
    University budget (AC-UBAP); University governance; University Press (C-UP); Vietnam Moratorium.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Ombudsman; Parking & Traffic (C-PRT); Privacy of Information (C-PPI); Public Events (C-PEV); Radiological Hazards Control (C-RHC).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 18, Folder 8)
    Relations with student government; Religious Activities (C-REL).
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 10/05/1970 - 01/18/1971 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Committee on Research (C-RES) minutes.
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 02/01/1971 - 06/07/1971 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 10/01/1970 - 06/01/1971 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Committee on Foreign Study Programs (C-FSP) subcommittee minutes for Austria, Britain, France.
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 10/01/1970 - 06/01/1971 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Committee on Foreign Study Programs (C-FSP) subcommittee minutes for Germany, Italy, Specialized Programs.
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 04/29/1970 - 07/29/1971 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    Committee on Graduate Studies minutes (includes Study of Graduate Education).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 19, Folder 6)
    Committee on Health (C-Hth); Honors Cooperative Program; Hoover Institution; housing.
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 11/20/1970 - 05/14/1971 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    Student Conduct Legislative Council (SCLC) minutes.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 19, Folder 8)
    Student Evaluation of Teaching (C-SET); Student Committee for Involvement in Politics (S.C.I.P.).
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Students on committees.
  - Academic Secretary Documents (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Student relations; Study of Education at Stanford (SES).
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 11/10/1970 - 08/09/1971 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Committee on Tresidder Union minutes; Trustees; Undergraduate Admissions & Financial Aids (C-UAFA) minutes.
  - Academic Secretary Documents, 09/24/1970 - 10/10/1970 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    Committee on Undergraduate Studies (C-US) minutes. [Note: meeting minutes from 10/17/1970 - 06/19/1971 are missing.]
  - 4th Senate, 05/20/1971 - 06/08/1972 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - 4th Senate, 05/20/1971 - 12/16/1971 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    Senate minutes & meeting calls.
  - 4th Senate, 01/06/1972 - 03/30/1972 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - 4th Senate, 04/03/1972 - 06/15/1972 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - 4th Senate, 09/29/1971 - 08/02/1972 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    Committee on Graduate Studies (C-GS) minutes (includes minutes of subcommittee on Graduate Special Programs 10/28/1971).
  - 4th Senate (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Study of Graduate Education at Stanford (SGES) report to the Senate: Part 1.
  - 4th Senate (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Study of Graduate Education at Stanford (SGES) report to the Senate: Part 2.
  - 4th Senate (Box 21, Folder 3)
    Study of Graduate Education at Stanford (SGES) report to the Senate: Part 3.
  - 4th Senate (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Study of Graduate Education at Stanford (SGES) report to the Senate: Part 4.
  - 4th Senate (Box 21, Folder 5)
    Health & Safety (P-HS); Hoover Institution; housing; Human Relations (HRC); Human Subjects in Research (P-UHSR). [Note: P = "panel"]
  - 4th Senate, 10/19/1971 - 05/26/1972 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - 4th Senate, 10/08/1971 - 03/31/1972 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Committee on Foreign Study Programs (C-FSP) minutes.
  - 4th Senate, 04/12/1972 - 05/31/1972 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - 4th Senate, 11/10/1971 - 06/05/1972 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - 4th Senate, 11/16/1971 - 06/02/1972 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    Committee on Foreign Study Programs (C-FSP) subcommittee minutes for Germany, Italy, Special Foreign Programs (C-FSP-SFP).
  - 4th Senate (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Faculty self-discipline (1).
  - 4th Senate (Box 22, Folder 2)
    Faculty self-discipline (2).
  - 4th Senate (Box 22, Folder 3)
    Faculty self-discipline: Franklin case.
  - 4th Senate, 10/29/1971 - 06/01/1972 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    Committee on Faculty & Staff Affairs (C-FSA) minutes.
  - 4th Senate (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Faculty & staff Professoriate & tenure; Commission on the Professoriate at Stanford (C-PS).
  - 4th Senate (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Placement service.
  - 4th Senate (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Privacy of information (C-PPI); Public Events (-PEV).
  - 4th Senate (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Relations with student government.
  - 4th Senate, 10/06/1971 - 01/13/1972 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - 4th Senate, 02/01/1972 - 05/23/1972 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - 4th Senate (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Search committees (various).
  - 4th Senate (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Senate attendance; Senate Charter; Senate election.
  - 4th Senate (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Senate guests; Senate rosters.
  - 4th Senate (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - 4th Senate, 11/02/1971 - 05/31/1972 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    Committee on Services to Students (C-SSt) minutes.
  - 4th Senate (Box 23, Folder 8)
    Stanford Public Law Advocates; Stanford Police (C-SSP & StC-RPV); Stanford Rehabilitation Movement.
  - 4th Senate (Box 23, Folder 9)
    Steering Committee election; Steering Committee procedures.
  - 4th Senate (Box 23, Folder 10)
    Student Conduct Legislative Council (SCLC); students on committees.
  - 4th Senate, 10/26/1971 - 05/28/1972 (Box 24, Folder 1)